39. The Dancing Plants of Yudhantani. Yes, you read that right. Plants that dance.
It's true. I've seen them. Yudhantani is a province in northeast Thailand. There are
no big cities there and not as many tourist attractions as there are in other parts of
the country. But there is one small plant nursery with one of the most amazing, but
little known, sites in the world. Simple green plants that look like common weeds. These
particular dancing plants are a hybrid of the Tani gyrant and the Chinese gyrant. The
pure parents can't dance as well as their hybrid child. The scientific name of this
type of plant is Codariocalyx motorius. Let's go back to the dancing. Walk through the nursery,
which is full of beautiful Thai orchids. Deep in the center of the nursery, surrounded
by brighter, more eye-catching plants, is a row of these green weeds. These are the
dancing plants. Stand in front of them and sing, the nursery worker says. At first it
feels silly to sing to a plant. I sing quietly and shyly and nothing happens. I think about
leaving, but I make myself stay and sing longer. Slowly the plants start opening and
closing their little leaves. The longer and louder I sing, the more they move. When I
stop, they stop. I test to see if my breath is making the leaves blow. Nope. They're moving
because I'm making a sound. It's incredible to interact with a plant this way. It makes
me think very deeply about the ways all living creatures are alive. Perhaps we're more connected
with the plant world than we think we are. Why the plant dances is still mysterious,
just another sign that we still have a lot to learn about our world.